Bitcoin's fallen back to $82,000.
But we have some big fundamental news.
Samsung bringing crypto to 82 million
people. And that's just one of the big
pieces of news that we have today. We
have a great guest who actually hasn't
been on the show before. We have Nick
Dukeov from Salana Foundation. We're
going to obviously talk about that
Samsung news and a lot more. Let's go.
That's dope.
>> Let's do
>> Good morning everybody and happy
Thursday to all of you who celebrate. We
just had one of the funnier technical
issues that we've ever had on this show.
We were sitting here with our background
on this amazing LED screen and all of a
sudden it turned literally into Sesame
Street and we realized we bought this
screen uh from Sesame Street a year ago
and I think that they've remotely taken
over our screen and might have hacked
us. They're probably going to take all
our crypto.
Oscar is truly a grouch.
Nick, sorry to bring you on with that
kind of amazing introduction. I just
didn't expect to have Sesame Street in
my background right before the show. How
are you, man?
>> I'm doing great. Thanks for having me
on.
>> You're welcome. So, listen, before we
dive into the deeply Salana stuff, we
have this interesting conversation once
again emerging about crypto security
that I think is top of mind in the news.
Here's the article on Coindesk. Bitcoin
slips below 83,000 as Ethereum
researchers bunker mode call divides
crypto. We obviously for some reason
have a very strange view there. uh
bunker mode uh divides crypto. So this
is now obviously the same guy Justin
Drake from the Ethereum Foundation who
was talking a lot about quantum and has
been a part of that debate now saying
that we're basically seeing a massive
acceleration in AI and we could just get
classical hacks that could put our
crypto at risk without even getting to
the point of quantum. I have to imagine
that this is something that you guys
have top of mind at Salana. uh not
necessarily this specific debate but the
risk of quantum and AI. So I mean how do
you frame what's going on right now and
if this is actually an acceleration?
>> So uh Salana has terrific quantum
resistance. Um something that you know
we're constantly working on on the
technical side. Uh the rally cry for
Salana of course is to increase
bandwidth and reduce latency making it
the highest performant um lowest cost
most scalable uh blockchain network in
the world. And quantum resistance of
course is important for resilience and
security and is uh something um that we
take very seriously.
>> Do you think that the risk is
accelerating
because of AI? Now quantum is quantum.
>> I think the world is getting weirder at
a very rapid pace and um but I think
that's on both sides of the ball, right?
You you've got offense, you've got
defense and and I think it's
accelerating on both sides of the ball.
Do you guys I mean is quantum do you
view that as a major risk in and of
itself even outside of the AI because
that was a huge part of the debate in
the first place as well.
>> Like I said I think it's something that
um the core devs take very seriously and
are are constantly ensuring that Salana
has best practices for.
>> Okay let's dive into this Samsung news
because it's it's really big. Samsung
integrates USDC to overhaul crossber
remittances for 82 million Galaxy users.
So, this is right into the 82 million
phones that are out there. Eligible
users will be able to send USDC abroad
or send local currency payouts to bank
accounts in more than 60 countries
starting late October. I think the most
compelling part of this news, which is
what we're seeing with most of these
integrations, is it entirely abstracts
away the crypto side, right? This is
just in your Samsung wallet that you
have on your phone and you have no idea
that it's happening with USDC. You have
no idea that it's happening on Salana.
You're just moving money.
>> 100% right. You know, we're entering a
tokenization super cycle. Uh the vision
that Salana has for internet capital
markets, which is connecting the world's
six billion internet users with the
world's uh many terrific productive
assets, including the US dollar, uh is a
foot. And I think this is great um
headway towards that goal. Uh prior to
this announcement, there was 13 million
stable coin holders on Salana. There's
about 15 billion stable coins in
circulation on Salana. for this
announcement today with Samsung bringing
Salana stable coins to another 80 plus
mil million users is incredible and and
ultimately there's two billion uh
Samsung holders in the world Samsung
device holders in the world and I'd love
to think that uh one day they're all uh
using Swan stable coins.
>> So let me ask you this. How do these
partnerships and announcements come
together? I've never really asked anyone
this. to Samsung, you know, call Salana
and say, "Hey, we're, you know, thinking
about doing this thing. Are you the guys
the blockchain or should we doing this
somewhere else?" Is there a competitive
pitches from multiple foundations? I
always wonder how they end up choosing
or do they just choose in a vacuum
because they do a little bit of research
and say it's faster, cheaper, and this
is the way to to approach it.
>> Yeah. Well, I I think that's
increasingly happening. Um and it's it's
it's thanks to the great work that not
only uh Salana team members but the
millions of Salana ecosystem uh
contributors all over the world um help
advance. So, uh, Salon is the most used
blockchain in the world. And if you're
looking at, you know, how to, uh, get
distribution for your product, if you're
looking for, uh, a technology that is
proven to be resilient and scalable, I
think increasingly large institutions
like Samsung, uh, look at Salon and say,
"Hey, this is fit for purpose. This is a
good blockchain, uh, for us to build on.
This is something we can trust." And
then they see others like we had an
announcement uh, DBP program with JP
Morgan last week. you know, when the
largest bank in the world uh is building
on Salana, I think that provides a lot
of um air cover for executives at other
institutions to say, "Hey, maybe we
should be building on Salana, too."
>> It's weird because I thought it was just
for meme coins.
>> Well, listen, memecoins proved the
technology. Um I I remember vividly when
the Trump memecoin dropped and in a
single day, uh Moon Pay KYCed three
million investors to buy the Trump
token. And you know there's there's not
you know many networks that can stand up
to that uh type of uh usage and and not
even hiccup.
>> Let me ask you when some of when
something like that happens obviously
those people come for a very specific
reason. They're non-crypto native. They
came because they want to support Trump
and hold the memecoin. How many of those
people would you say just you know
ballpark end up sticking around and
doing something else in crypto? not
necessarily on Salana, but you know, you
got three million people in KYC. They
buy the Trump token, they buy it, it
goes down. Is that a, you know, is it a
window into more activity or do they
just basically do that one thing?
>> Well, that's a great question, Scotty.
And I think, you know, as with anything,
somebody has to do one thing before they
do end things. And so, you know,
whatever it is that brings a user to
Salana for the first time, whether it's
meme coins, prediction markets, stable
coins, uh, real world assets, gaming,
you know, there's so many different
things that people can do on the Salana
blockchain. and um whatever it is that
brings them for the first time once they
use Salana um it just feels like
everything else they use on the internet
it's it's fast it's it's um uh highly
performant it it kind of just um fades
away into the background something that
you said about the Samsung initiative
and I think that's why Salon is the
chain of choice for for so many users
and so many institutions
>> yeah that UXUI problem to me has through
every cycle been the major elephant in
the room for crypto adoption and now it
just seems like crypto adoption is
happening at infrastructure and
plumbing, right? And I think that that
was always the boring path that it was
going to end up having to take, right?
Like a grandma was never going to, you
know, like uh go download a MetaMask
wallet to figure out how to move a
stable coin and figure out her private
keys. Right? Now it's just your Samsung
wallet.
>> Exactly.
>> Okay. So, talk about
Samsung's adding this specifically for
crossborder payments and remittances is
what they're saying. How that that seems
oddly specific for the announcement. It
feels like this would just be they're
integrating stable coins for anything,
right? Is it is there some specific
functionality
crossber payments really is the killer
use case? Like I'll give you an example.
Um I was in Europe recently with some
friends from all over the world and you
know we were settling up um after
splitting a bill and uh you know my
accounts are in US dollars you know if
somebody else's accounts are in British
pounds and another person's accounts are
in euros and another person's accounts
are in Japanese yen um you know their
their actual bank accounts that's
actually like very hard to move money
you know via you know something like a a
Vinmo or or or something more
traditional. Of course, Vinmo now
supports PYUSD on Salon, and so they're
trying to do the same same thing as
Samsung. But with stable coins, you can
pay or remit um US dollars to anyone
anywhere in the world. And I think
that's really the power of stable coins
today. We we obviously are seeing and
and expect to see more utilization of
stable coins for merchant payments, for
uh bill payments, for um you know,
institutional DVP and and and wholesale
payment of money. But you know today I
think crossber is the killer use case
and that's why western union that's why
biceerve that's why moneygram um have
all built on salana.
So we have this interesting situation
where we have the Salanas and the
Ethereums and the decentralized
protocols that crypto people have come
to love obviously with massive adoption
of stable coins and tokenized equities
but we also have the incumbents entering
the race right so you have a consortium
of the biggest banks and institutions on
the planet launching their own stable
coin which was announced you know two
weeks ago you have the community and
regional banks launching bank chain
whatever that one was because they're
afraid of being squeezed by that bigger
chain by the big banks and crypto on the
other side and then you have open USD
from a consortium once again and I don't
believe in these consortiums can
necessarily be successful but from a
consortium of fintexs led by stripe
right and you have arc with tempo so it
seems like there's all the this major
bifurcation of the way that people are
going to approach stable coin adoption
how much of that will naturally acrue to
a salana versus some walled garden that
one of these consortiums creates because
they don't want it to end up on a you
know decentralized open protocol. Well,
you mentioned OUSD that launched on
Salana with I think the deepest
liquidity and and that's, you know, one
of the main reasons people choose
Salana. You know, kind of reason one
would be the technology. There's there's
nothing more proven and performant as
Salana for that type of use case. And
then the second thing is distribution.
Um Salana is the most used blockchain in
the world. Has users all over the world.
Um and I that's ultimately what um these
issuers are looking for is people to you
to use the product that they bring on
chain. Um the thing I say all the time
is like Maslo's kind of hierarchy of
blockchain is something like at the at
the bottom is like the basic needs like
is it is it fast is it cheap then it's
like is it useful does it have utility
then it is it a delight to use that's
the top of the pyramid and I think
Salana hits the mark on on all of those.
Yeah, the old trillemma, right? But uh
the but I had had a conversation years
ago with Tuli actually and I think I
kind of made like a Lord of the Rings
joke, you know, one chain to rule them
all and he very flat out said years ago,
yes, we can do that. You don't need any
other blockchains that everything can
happen on Salana. Is that still like the
general approach even in context of all
these things that you're seeing
launched? So, you know, uh I'm a stoic
with respect to my philosophy. Like
there's things within our control,
there's things outside of our control. I
think within the sphere of control that
the Salana Foundation has like we're
still very committed to the original vi
vision that Toli and and Salana
co-founders had, which is this this idea
of a global state machine where there
can be a single venue where all
liquidity uh can be and all users can
be. That said, you know, people are
going to do, you know, what what they
need to do um, you know, to meet, you
know, various um, needs for their
business. And that may include private
blockchains. Uh, that may include other
chains that may be fit for purpose for a
very particular use case. Um, but the
good news is that Salana is
interoperable with all of them and is
increasingly the place where um,
ultimately these these uh, assets
settle. And so I think that's the
important thing about the tokenization
super cycles. Even if something may you
know kind of like originate somewhere
else ultimately I think it's going to
trade uh and or settle on the Salana
public blockchain.
>> So I I assume with the Salana Foundation
you have to be laser focused in certain
verticals that you believe will be the
next you know uh places to target for
meaningful adoption. It sounds like
stable coins and tokenization are pretty
much those verticals right? Are there
others that I'm missing?
>> Well, I mean, within within
tokenization, obviously tokenized
equities is a very exciting one. We got
the innovation exemption from the SEC a
couple weeks ago and and just today um
the Wall Street Journal uh announced uh
that Securitize is bringing um tokenized
stock trading for US investors on the
Salana blockchain for a dozen or so uh
equities uh the fang stocks uh and the
big AI hyperscalers. very exciting um
that securitize chose Salana uh to to do
this. Um and the the key thing here is
the uh tokenized uh stocks will be
available to us investors. Historically
to date uh most of these tokenized
equities have been available to non US
um holders and securitize has done um
you know the hard work over many years
to uh have the regulatory infrastructure
to support uh this type of initiative.
And the article also mentions that uh it
is planned for these stocks on Salana to
trade in the uh tokenized stock venue
the TSV uh that NY is launching with
OKX. You're wearing an OKX hoodie right
now. So that's good news uh for the
hoodies as well.
>> It is I was going to ask you about that
because this so clearly even though the
innovation exemption is not officially a
rule uh a lot of people are moving
forward as if it will be right. So it
seems like that's a a foregone
conclusion as far as OKX and NIS and ICE
are certainly concerned and securitized
here. I didn't get a chance to really
dig into this story because you
basically told me two minutes before we
went on that this had happened. And I
completely missed it when it says
Securitize is rolling out tokenized
stocks for US investors and that's the
big unlock specifically. How does this
work? Where is Securitize making these
available to US investors?
>> So on if you go to Securitize's website,
you can KYC and then um buy the the
stocks. You put your wallet in and and
you buy the stocks or uh I believe they
also have a their own wallet that you
can use as well. Um I'm sure um more to
come on on how this all will be rolled
out, but very exciting. Um and um you
know, Salana is the place for tokenized
equities. I think something like 95% of
all tokenized equities trading volume
happens on Salana today.
>> Yes. I honestly didn't know that you
like Securitize had a retail front end
that you could go into to actually do
this. So that's actually big news to me
in and of itself and feels like the
first test case before this hits Schwab
in E Trade and we're doing the same
things there, right? Because once
securitizer one of them proves a model
and makes it available to us investors,
that's going to put everybody else on
notice that this is coming.
>> Well, and you mentioned Schwab Trade.
Both of them currently have a capability
for soul uh which had been announced and
so um you can imagine that SPL tokens
which is the tokenization
uh program on Salana uh to enable the um
you know buy sell hold of something like
tokenized equities or other real world
assets would be enabled too.
>> This stuff is happening so fast
it's crazy. How long have you been at
Salana Foundation?
>> Uh just under three and a half years.
>> Okay. So like did you when you took that
uh you know took that position and took
that on did you have a timeline in mind
for all of these things and all these
things that are happening were those at
top of list for what you wanted to see
happen when you joined because to me it
feels like we're doing the hockey stick
thing where it was kind of flat and
everybody talked about it and now it's
just you know vertical
>> you know listen I we we always want it
to be faster and and want more at the
within the Salana ecosystem. So um you
know there's a lot more work to be done
but I think where we are today is a
great um foundation for for for more to
come.
>> So I I read something you said you said
seven of the 29 globally global system
systemically important banks are
building on Salana and you expect that
to be half within a year what like a I
mean who is it and b what are they doing
like when it's you know when we say
building on Salana what are they
building on Salana? Yeah. So, Morgan
Stanley has a sole ETF. They also have
uh buy, sell, hold on Erade. Uh JP
Morgan issued commercial paper. Galaxy's
commercial paper and and did that trade
on Salana with Franklin Templeton and
Coinbase buying it. Um in December, uh
they have a money fund on Salana and the
DBP program I mentioned for settlement
of of securities transactions. Uh city
uh issued a white paper on a trade
finance pilot they did on the Salana
network. A society general has a euro
stable coin. State Street has a money
fund. Uh, Standard Chartered has custody
for Salana. Um, BNY has a range of
offerings from custody, stable coin
mint, burn, and fund administration. And
stay tuned for um, some big
announcements at our flagship Breakpoint
conference in London, November 16th and
17th. You're not going to want to miss
that.
>> It's my 50th birthday.
>> Happy birthday.
>> Well, not yet, but I'm gonna be 50.
>> You don't look a day over 40. I I I'm
told I don't look a day over 48, but you
know, whatever. I'll take I'll take
Don't look a day over 40. I I mean,
listen, I have some friends who are 50
and they they they look old. So, I I'll
take that as a win. Um so, uh is there
any high anything that you can preview
us that we might uh hear about at
Breakpoint?
>> You know, listen, there'll be some other
announcements between now and then, but
you're you're going to want to show up
in London. Uh it's our biggest event of
the year. Last year was in Abu Dhabi. We
had over 7,000 attendees from over 100
countries. We expect a similar uh
showing this year in in London and um uh
we hope to see you there, Scott. So I I
had a conversation with Carlos from
Securitize going going back to that news
when we were at consensus and I brought
up the fact that you know it was huge
news that the DTCC was going to be
settling on tokenized rails and you know
throughout the 4.7 quadrillion a year in
settlement or whatever lud ludicrous
number that was and he sort of made the
point that that wasn't very exciting. He
said, you know, for DTTC to do this,
it's just literally them like updating
their computers and technology and their
plumbing, and that really will not acrue
to anybody else, and it's very much a
closed garden. This goes back to the
question I asked before about sort of
the pushpull beside between choosing a
public blockchain or or creating a
private one. Is there a world where a
lot of this ends up on these private
blockchains and we don't really get to
participate?
>> Like I said, I ultimately think the
settlement is going to happen on public
rails. Um so I do believe that even if
some of the orchestration happens on
private ledger that ultimately people
will want to um settle um on a public
blockchain because that's where the
liquidity is that's where the on and off
ramps are. You know that's that's that's
where the connectivity is and I think
Salana will be the the winner there. Um
I also think that for tokenized equities
you know there's a few emergent models.
You've mentioned and we we talked about
secure ties and then of course DTC.
You've got the rapper model that has
where you know they essentially create a
structure to make their tokens
permissionless and available to global
investors. You've got securitize taking
a very regulated approach as a transfer
agent. Um you know they they've got an
an announced partnership with computer
share uh and then the TSV with um OKX
and and and ICE. And then you've got uh
the entitlement model that DTC has where
you know it's uh held in street name um
and they're providing additional utility
uh for those uh tokenized equities. So
you know I don't know exactly how it's
going to play out but I think that
Salana B will be a winner regardless.
Yeah, I I mean I tend to agree. I think
it'll all generally go to uh the
superior blockchains and I don't think
that's going to be DTCC DTCC chain, you
know, personally. And you can already
see the growth here. I mean, I have this
for Salana. Justin took equities on
Salana hit an all-time high of 1.2
million holders with 775,000
joining in September alone. Like there's
that hockey stick. This is to me it's
just crazy.
>> It's a good start. Um, you know, there's
there's six billion internet users. Uh,
we want to reach all of them. So, quite
quite a long way to go.
>> Who are these people? Like, you know,
when you talk about 775,000 joining in
September, is there a way that we can
take a look and see what kind of
investor these are? Are these the crypto
natives that are, you know, like super
interested in flipping meme coins and
now they see a stock over there that
they can get in their portfolio and so
they're playing around? Or are these
long-term investors that have found a
way to, you know, gain access to
equities they didn't have before because
they're somewhere in the world where
they don't have access to US capital
markets? Both.
>> Yeah, I think it's all of the above,
right? And um, you know, we're talking
about US equities uh, for international
holders. I think what we we'll also see
more of is international equities being
brought to US investors. Um it's highly
inefficient um for US investors to
access uh stocks outside of the US. So
an example would be SKHEX. Uh the
premium that you pay on an ADR is
something like 30% uh for a share uh as
traded uh in the US. And you know that's
just fee capture that we've got to
collapse. And I think that's where
something like a Salana can really be
helpful to drive costs down for
investors around the world and and
improve access to to assets as well.
>> Any idea what 1.2 million holders, which
I guess that's from October 2nd, so
that's a week ago. I'm assuming it's
doubled by now. Uh but any idea how much
value that represents?
>> So there's something I think in the
order of like 700 million of tokenized
equity supply right now. There's 4.3
billion of real world assets overall on
Salana. Those are growing very very
quickly. I think we started the year
around a billion uh total real world
assets. So forex uh growth within the
year um and uh I would expect that to
continue at least at that rate.
>> So obviously we've talked about
stablecoin, we've talked about tokenized
equities. We had a lot of uh very
compelling narratives in crypto in years
past where you know whether via NFTts or
tokenized versions of things we would
start seeing our mortgages and our car
payments and all these other things
coming on chain those seem to be dwarfed
by obviously the size of capital markets
coming on chain but are those still
things that are happening maybe we can
even just go through them you know NFTTS
gaming metaverse all the fun that we had
in the past like are any of those things
still bubbling
>> well I think I think the blockchain
serves as a great um laboratory for
financial innovation. And so this is why
all these things have you know started
on chain and um find a use case uh and
ultimately as with all innovation
there's you know a product life cycle
where it goes through the trough of
disillusionment and then ultimately
finds um you know some sticky success
and and I think we're past that trough
of disillusionment for tokenized
equities. There there was that trough
for sure. People were saying is real
assets even a thing? like you said, we
were talking about this 5 years ago and
then, you know, it kind of wasn't a
thing and now it's popping off. So, I
think um the way to think about uh
blockchain is it's it's really a
laboratory for financial innovation. And
some things will work, some things
won't, but the things that work because
of its interoperability and global
connectivity can just go absolutely
vertical. And that's what we're seeing
with tokenized equities. And I think
we'll see it with some of the other
categories that you you talked about.
Maybe their time wasn't right a year or
two ago. Maybe it will be a year or two
from now.
>> Yeah. I mean, we that that's what we do
in crypto, right? We we have a really
good idea, we create 99% stupid things
around that idea. It creates a massive
bubble and then four to eight years
later, we come back with the one killer
thing from that idea that actually
rises. But to to be fair, that's not
entirely different than the dot bubble
in the 90s. Right.
>> Turns out the internet's a thing. Turns
out the internet's a thing, right?
>> Yeah. The internet's a thing. And you
know, you may have had 9,000 companies
wash out, but the nine that emerged were
the biggest companies in the world for
the next few decades,
>> right?
>> I I think that's actually a pretty good
correlary for for what's likely to
happen here. I still don't see why G
like I I never I don't understand why
gaming hasn't happened. I thought that
was one of the most natural fits for
blockchain when you looked at how much
money people were spending in game
ecosystems to be able to take any of
that value out. Well, I think I think
gaming has happened, but maybe you know
the framing of a game has changed. So, I
would argue that a prediction market is
a game and that's a game that is
absolutely
wildly successful and and it's largely
thanks to to blockchain. So, maybe the
definition of a game is as we were
thinking about it, you know, kind of
with a controller playing like this, the
financial markets game is is a different
one. Um,
just a
>> future markets are really addictive. So,
like, you know, I I uh
>> I don't gamble too much, but I've had
fun just kind of testing it out. I I I
think that uh I can't tell if it's the
greatest in innovation or if we're going
down a very dangerous path of everybody
gambling on everything all the time.
>> Well, I'm sure you've seen some use
cases which are really quite novel and
exciting around um insurance. Have you
seen like uh the bar in New York that um
hedged against the New York Knicks
winning the championship and offered
everyone a free beer or whatever if they
won and which they did and they had
hedged and it was all good and bar was
full. They made tons of money and I
think that's a super cool innovative use
case and I I think that's exactly what I
mean when I talk about the blockchain as
a innovation lab for financial products.
>> Yeah. I mean, and interestingly, like
it's a lab for speculation, too. And
some of that speculation turns into real
things. I mean, 99% of what people have
done in crypto is trying to buy
something that they can sell for higher
later, right? I don't think that that's
that's a bad thing. But then the NYX
kind of example comes out from me uh you
know, gambling with leverage on the
weather,
>> which is ridiculous.
>> Lot of new technologies look like toys
when they first start getting started.
So, uh,
what else is exciting you right now in
the market?
>> You know, Samsung bringing Salana to 80
million wallets and secure ties bringing
stocks to US investors. That's not
enough for you, Scott. Come on. No,
>> you never know. There might be something
I don't even know about.
>> Like I said, I, you know, welcome you
and all the listeners to join us in
London, uh, mid- November for
Breakpoint. We'll have a lot more
announcements then.
>> What do you think of the market right
now?
Uh, crypto market or stock market?
>> Crypto market. I don't I can't even
start to think about the stock market. I
call every one of my hedge fund friends
and stuff like every week and they're
all like, I'm getting slaughtered. I
don't know what's going on. I can't
figure anything out. So, a consensus is
that nobody understands the US stock
market. But crypto, you know, seems to
be having its little cycle thing. I was
one of those cycles dead, four year
cycles dumb people last October, and now
I'm one of the dumb people who is
wondering if we're just about to cycle
up into the four-year cycle again.
Well, you got a couple things happening
and and yeah, I think the um crypto
market is related to stock market at
least to some extent. You had the
hyperscalers attracting all the
liquidity in the world and that of
course is partially liquidity coming
from crypto markets and then now you've
got the dollar debasement trade
happening and I think in a bigger way
you know us crossed that uh 40 uh uh
threshold which you know put people um
uh on edge and and you know we saw rates
spike um and we saw crypto um start to
um catch a bid after that. And so I I
think you know two things are happening
that are a bit intension and that's why
crypto is chopping a little bit but um I
like the setup. I you know ultimately I
think the use cases are increasingly
clear for blockchain. You know it's here
to stay. Um more people are going to use
it. More people are going to become
familiar with it. More people are going
to invest in it. And ultimately I think
that's going to um drive prices up.
>> You have a couple more minutes. I didn't
look at the calendar for how much she
goes. There's actually I didn't talk
about this uh yesterday because it just
didn't end up being appropriate in a
broader macro conversation, but sign of
the times. Pudgy Penguins owner shuts
down its abstract blockchain after tens
of millions in losses. It seems like
I guess with everything crypto, but
we're having a natural consolidation now
uh and that the layer 2 narrative beyond
maybe you know those sponsored by major
corporations uh is probably sort of
dying. But I mean, did you expect that
all these layer twos would eventually
disappear, that we'd be seeing what we
are in kind of the ancient blockchains
dying space? I mean, I've been kind of
uh I expected this, you know, to to some
degree, not to them specifically, but
I've been saying for a very while long
while now, especially with AI and going
back to the hacking conversation, that
anything old that doesn't have like a
robust team and security budget is
basically just going to get hacked and
drained to zero or is going to
disappear.
Listen, I I think Salana um has been
pretty resolute in the belief that um
we're building towards a a global state
machine, you know, single liquidity
venue um with an incredibly highly
performant blockchain. Um it's very hard
to build and scale a blockchain. Um our
president Lily sometimes jokes that she
wouldn't wish it on her worst enemy. And
you know I think um when Vidilik you
know kind of abandoned the uh L2 roadmap
it put a lot of pressure on on some of
these networks but ultimately you know
something like Apy you know their token
is on Salana Securize uh even had a
private chain uh called converge for
some time and and they're now scaling on
Salana. So I I think that um the phase
of hey I'm going to run my own
infrastructure and you know my my own
technology platform. I I think folks are
recognizing it's hard enough um you know
to do one thing really really well and
and let let's let Salana do what they do
really well which is you know being the
the best blockchain in the world.
>> Yeah. That's what makes me wonder even
about OpenUSD and all of these
consortiums and Arc from Circle and
Tempo. Like I get that everybody wants
their own blockchain. And I certainly
understand why they would want to
collect the fees instead of hand them
elsewhere. But once again, when I saw
all these layer twos sort of appearing
in the last cycle, I said they're all
the same thing. Like why why do we need
another layer two? Like why do we need
any of these things if you know the
existing blockchains can already do
everything that they're trying to build?
Is there some new innovation that I'm
missing from arc or tempo
or abstract or you name it, right?
>> Listen, we're we're we're going to keep
keep grinding and and I think the
market's going to continue to recognize
um you know, Salana's great tech and um
they're going to launch tokens there.
They're going to use it. They're going
to build their applications there and um
that's what we continue to see. It's
funny. I remember it must have been
2021. The big conversation was, "Oh my
god, there's going to be a billion
people coming on chain and we not going
to have the block space for them. Like,
what are we going to do?" Oh, oh, oh,
what was me? And now it's like, we have
so much block space.
We have so many chains. Who's going to
use all these things? It was a complete
flip. Like, everybody overbuilt, I
think, because they thought they could
make money on a token.
And here we are. I I I would say slow
than fast, right? It's like that chart
that you pulled up where you know things
are going vertical right now. Um you you
you know if you look at uh public
infrastructure as a as a correlary um
you know when uh cities add additional
lanes on uh highways like car more cars
come to use those additional lanes. So
so I I do expect the traffic uh and and
utilization will come and um uh you know
Salana's ready for it. Yeah, I agree. I
just don't think it'll come to L2 number
47.
Okay, let me ask you one more question
before I let you go. How much does
the price of the asset impact the
sentiment sentiment and how much do
these fundamental things we're
discussing actually end up impacting the
price in the short term?
>> Yeah. So um the
utility token for a network and uh the
adoption of that network whether we like
it or not do tend to you know have some
correlation. Um and crypto is a
reflexive asset when it when it's going
down it you know continues to go down.
When it's up it it can continue to go up
and um the I would say the good news is
that Salana ecosystem wins in both
markets. Salana has a culture of uh
building in the bear. Um we're an
incredibly resilient ecosystem. Um you
know when when times were very very hard
after FTX and so went all the way down
to $8. Um people did not stop building
on the network and and that's why you
see Salana where it is today. Um you
know three or four years later from from
from that um bare market. Um we've been
in a bare market since the beginning of
the year and and look at you know all of
the incredible things that have happened
um you know within the ecosystem during
that time. um all of tokenized equities
popping off you know folks like
incredible institutions like JP Morgan
and and Samsung adopting Salana and then
when things are going up that's great
too because you know more people start
um learning about uh the token want to
be curious about the technology start
using the network um they tell their
friends and you know that of course you
know creates more growth and adoption um
last November um the first uh Salana
ETPs came to market in the United states
bitwise now has over a billion dollars
of of aum in it you know kind of even
you know amidst um you know most of that
attracting most of that capital in a
bare market so um I'm bullish uh I think
Salana as an ecosystem is incredible um
whether the price is low or high doesn't
matter uh the builders keep building
technology keeps hardening uh you usage
keeps growing and um you know higher
>> I mean I agree I just think it's so
funny in crypto with any asset where I
guess any asset but specifically crypto
nothing's better marketing than higher
prices like everything becomes easier
after a 20% up week like all of a sudden
Bitcoin's back is the key to the
debasement trade uh you know over 24
hours because it went from 60 to 75 you
know and I just find it so hilarious
that really at the end of the day people
just need to see the price go up to
start believing all the narratives that
everybody's been screaming about the
entire bare
I also noticed you love tennis.
>> I do love tennis. Are you a tennis
player?
>> I I was a prolific
local high school tennis player. Uh I
was number one on my local high school
team. I was very good in my little
vacuum. And if I went out to uh you know
play super competitively, I got my ass
whipped. But yeah, I love tennis.
>> Well, we should get out and hit
sometime.
>> Yeah. Awesome. Where are all the hats?
Are they they've just they
>> those are all signed hats, you know, Ben
Shelton. Um Lindsey Davenport, Andy
Rodic.
>> So Ben Shelton, Ben Shelton, uh I I
lived in Gainesville, Florida for many
years. That's where I grew up. He went
to the University of Florida. But when I
was there about a year and a half ago,
uh and uh I was I was hitting and he was
hitting on the court next to me.
>> I started smacking in his direction so I
could say that I was hitting with Ben
Shelton.
>> So it was funny. Yeah, I'm the kind of
guy who will do that. But yeah, he was
he's an incredible Yeah, incredible
tennis player.
>> 150 mile per hour surf.
>> Yeah, not bad. I wasn't uh returning
those. That would kill me actually. I
would die. Uh so Nick, really was great
to have you on. Love to have you back uh
in the notsodistant future. Really great
perspective, man. Thank you very much.
>> Thank you.
>> All right,
great. We had that that was a welltimed
because obviously uh we had such big
news today from from from Salana. But uh
a lot of what Nick said and what we
continue to hear from guests really does
like align with the way that I've been
uh viewing things and assuming things
would progress. I I hate seeing all of
these older blockchains fail and I hate
seeing people lose money, but I think
it's just a natural uh part of what is
coming, which is a consolidation of the
blockchains. I just wanted to take a
very quick look because Bitcoin
obviously uh is looking shaky today. So,
I was just going to pull up the chart
with you guys, which we got right here.
This is the Bitcoin weekly chart. Uh so,
a lot of people are panicking right now,
but I just want to show you something.
Zoom in right here. Obviously, we have
Bitcoin here trading at now under
$82,000, which means it's over. It's
going to zero, and we're all going to be
poor. So, congratulations.
Um, I'm I'm homeless now. Uh, but as you
can see, we had Bitcoin making the high
around 127ish, you know, in the 126 is
low, lower high, lower low, lower high,
lower low, breaking above 82,800 and
then holding there and then testing it
as the weekly chart last week. That was
confirmation that that bearish trend was
over. And yes, I see right now on the
weekly chart we are trading slightly
below it. So I just pulled back to the
last bare market to see if that also
happened when we made that uh
higher uh higher high and it made the
higher high here and came back down and
dipped on multiple occasions back below
that line before heading up. So to me I
take a look at this is a very very
healthy retest that you would want of
the area that was once support even if
it goes below and also like I would not
be surprised at all just for the record
for it to come back and test the 50 MA
which is all the way down here at 77. To
me that wouldn't really be a big deal.
All I can say is that once you make that
higher high and break above every
meaningful MA dips are for buying. My
arch public I noticed uh believe it was
buying this morning. It was either last
night or this morning I started to get
the alert that Arch Public was buying
the dip again. And by the way, it sold
right at 88,000. So the is
incredible. Uh taking a look at
prediction markets. When will Bitcoin
cross $100,000 again.
These are the markets we got.
Before November 2026, 8%. Okay, I mean
that would be a pretty big move. before
December 2026, 22% for January 2027,
32%. I would say that people are still
very bearish on 100K considering 100K is
uh not that far from the recent highs
that we just made. So, I still think
sentiment is much more negative than it
deserves to be. And man, I am a Bitcoin
buyer right now. Uh by the way, I always
forget to tell you, but you can see
right up there, we do work with uh
Koshi. I actually use their prediction
markets quite often myself, as I said.
Not that I'm a gambler, but it's really
fun to bet on the Dodgers. Won those
last two bets, just going to be honest.
Um, and uh, you can get 25 bucks for
trading 25 bucks, which you're going to
go use it anyways. Prediction Markets,
they've got pers, all kinds of
incredible products. You should go check
them out in the description down below.
I'm trying to remember. We got someone
awesome tomorrow, but my brain is not uh
functioning at full capacity. I'll tell
you this weekend, uh,
our two podcasts for Saturday and
Sunday, tomorrow's Matt Hogan. Thank
you. Matt Hogan, I told you it was
someone awesome. So, the next three
days, Matt Hogan,
Peter Schiff,
and this last one, man, I don't really
know, but I'm going to do it. Hunter
Biden. It's Hunter Biden. Hunter Biden.
Haven't decided what I'm gonna ask him.
We were kind of talk kicking it around
here like hey what happened with your
token that you know they did a poor
smoke postmortem on that I guess over
the days. Um I want to know if uh what
drugs he likes.
Why does his dad hate us? Stuff like
that. Maybe I'll ask him. I don't know
man. Peter Ship and Hunter Biden one
weekend. You know, I already recorded
the Peter Ship conversation though,
honestly, and we I'm told you I said I
think it to Noel and we barely talked
about Bitcoin and I think you will find
which I've been saying from the
beginning, gold bugs like Peter Schiff
and us agree on 99% of everything. Just
don't agree on the asset uh to use to
protect yourself from what's coming. And
so I think that uh Peter Schiff when you
take out the opinion on Bitcoin, he may
be like the best Bitcoin maximalist we
have for understanding why you would
need Bitcoin and the government. So it's
going to be incredible. Justin people
say no not shift. I'm telling you it is.
He does not hate on Bitcoin at all. In
fact, he was like it's performed
surprisingly well.
All right guys, I will see you tomorrow
obviously on the Daily Wolf today on
Yahoo at noon. That is all we have for
you today. Goodbye. I will see you
later.
That's dope.